It's May 1975, and Peter Gabriel has just played the last post on his oboe
我们回到1975年5月 Peter Gabriel在上台和Genesis进行
before he joins genesis on stage
最后一次Lamb专辑的演出之前 在排练时最后一次演奏了双簧管
to perform The Lamb Lies Down on Broadway for the last time.
Peter Gabriel: Vocals
Two months later, the band were writing and rehearsing
两个月之后 乐队在他们经常去的录音棚里 写新歌 并进行排练
new songs at their usual rehearsal studio,
the basement of the Una Billings School of Dance, in London's Shepherd's Bush.
那个录音室是在伦敦 是这个舞蹈学校的地下室
Phil Collins: Drums
Tony Banks: Keyboard
Mike Rutherford: Bass
In those initial sessions it was only Banks, Collins and Rutherford jamming together
刚开始排练的时候 只有Banks Collins Rutherford在一起围绕
with the basics of both Dance on a Volcano and Squonk
Dance on a Volcano和Squonk进行即兴创作
这两首歌Steve Hackett在当时没有参与创作
being written without Steve Hackett.
现在播放：Hands Of The Priestess by Steve Hackett
Steve Hackett: Guitar
Hackett was still putting the final touches to his own recording,
Steve Hackett那时在完成录制他自己的专辑
The Voyage of the Acolyte together.
也就是 The Voyage of the Acolyte
He'd been recording this over June and July that year.
在1975的六月和七月 他一直在录制这张专辑
"I'm writing the album throughout the whole of the lamb tour." ("I" refer to Hackett)
他说他在Lamb专辑巡演途中 一直在写这张专辑
He claimed that the quiet, late-night writing sessions helped calm his onstage nerves.
他还说 在后半夜安静的时候写歌 能帮他克服怯场
Much of the Acolyte album stands equal to the Lamb,
很多Acolyte专辑里的歌质量能和Lamb媲美
In fact the Acolyte's epic closer, the Shadow of the Hierophant
实际上 这张专辑史诗般的结尾曲 The Shadow of the Hierophant
had been co-written with Mike Rutherford.
是他和Mike Rutherford一起写的
And it was rehearsed by Genesis back in the Foxtrot days.
而且在Genesis录制Foxtrot专辑的时候 他们就排练过了
Tower Struck Down is another track that Hackett had also offered up
Hackett还给他的Genesis队友提供了Tower Struck Down
to his Genesis Band mates, only to have it rejected.
现在播放：Tower Struck Down by Steve Hackett
不过被乐队否决了
Whilst the band had managed to keep Gabriel's departure
虽然这时 乐队仍在严密保住Gabriel离队的秘密
at closely guarded secrets up to this point,
rumours of the singer's departure were
关于乐队主唱Gabriel离队的传闻
starting to circle it in the press over the summer.
在那个夏天一直在媒体中流传
And by the 16th of August edition of Melody Maker, the secret was out:
而在8月16日的Melody Maker杂志上 消息还是公开了
Gabriel had left Genesis.
Gabriel已经离开了Genesis乐队
And soon after that,
在此之后 唱片公司收到很多想应聘歌手的试音带
注：唱片公司指Charisma Record，标志是《爱丽丝漫游仙境》里的Mad Hatter
Charisma Records received hundreds of audition tapes for the replacement singer.
With many spelling doom for the band, they started recording
在舆论普遍唱衰乐队的情况下 他们在十月入棚
in London's Trident Studios in October with the producer David Henschel.
和制作人David Henschel一起录制新专辑
He'd previously been their assistant engineer since the days of Nursery Cryme.
从录制Nursery Cryme开始 他就是助理录音工程师了
At this point the band had no idea who would sing vocals on the new album
在这时 乐队还没想好由谁来唱这张新专辑
or if indeed there would be vocals at all.
或者说 这张专辑是否需要包括人声
Tony Banks has stated that
Tony Banks说过 这张专辑从来没有打算像成品那样 录进人声
the album was never intended to be as vocal as it ultimately turned out.
Now this suggests that the band
这暗示了 当时乐队曾经考虑过纯音乐方向
may have been considering a more instrumental route.
And when you consider the popularity of jazz fusion
当时融合爵士乐和纯器乐作品十分流行
and instrumental music in general at that time,
plus Collins' own involvement with Brand X, this is quite plausible.
加上Collins也加入了融合爵士乐队Brand X 这么想应该没错
During the recording sessions Gabriel himself visited them
在录音的时候 Gabriel亲自拜访了他们
and he commented to Melody Maker that
他向Melody Maker说 他们的声音更加清脆 比之前的更好了
they had a much crisper and clearer sound.
He said that the band sounded better than ever.
And also, referred to their newfound speedy work rate.
这里 我提一下他们全新的工作节奏 相当高效
The Trick of The Tail taking only one month to record
相较于上一张专辑四个月的录制时间
compared to the four months for the Lamb. It does have something of a point.
他们这回只花了一个月就录好了 确实有点能力哈
The entire Trick of the Tail album was recorded instrumentally,
在很多的歌手到录音室应聘歌手之前
before various singers were invited into the studio.
这张专辑的器乐部分就已经录好了
These prospective vocalists were asked to sing on
应聘主唱的人被要求歌唱Sqounk和I Know What I Like
both Squonk and I Know What I Like.
It was ultimately Collins's own singing of Squonk
结果Collins唱的Squonk十分合适
that convinced the others that he was the right man for the job.
这说服了其他队友 他们觉得Phil是当主唱的最合适人选
However, it's thought that up to 10 other singers
话说回来 据说当时最多有10个歌手应邀来到
were invited into Trident Studios to become the new Genesis frontman.
录音室 来应聘Genesis的主唱
One of those was Bernie Frost.
其中一个是Bernie Frost
At that time he was the songwriting partner for Status Quo.
这时 他是Status Quo的创作伙伴
He'd also played in various sessions with Phil Collins.
他和Phil Collins也在一起录过几次音
What you're about to hear is an isolated vocal track from Bernie Frost,
你接下来将听到的 是Bernie Frost演唱过的一首歌与
added into an instrumental version of a Genesis track, I'm sure you'll know.
Genesis某首歌的器乐相结合 这首歌各位应该很熟悉
It gives an impression of how Bernie may have sounded
我觉得如果Bernie真成了Genesis主唱的话
if he'd been chosen to be the Genesis frontman. Let's have a listen.
就会是这样了吧 我们来听听吧
注：不熟悉的话，器乐部分来自Mad Man Moon
Another potential vocalist was singer Steve Gould from the band Rare Bird.
另一个潜在的主唱选择是Rare Bird的主唱Steve Gould
And this is a group that had played many concerts with Genesis in the early 70s,
在七十年代早期 他们和Genesis乐队在一起演出过很多次
and were also on the Charisma Record label.
而且都签在了同一家唱片公司
What you're about to hear next is another isolated vocal track
接下来要听到的 是一首由Rare Bird演奏的歌曲 Sympathy
from a Rare Bird song, Sympathy.
It's been added to a demo recording of Ripples.
它的人声叠录在早期Ripples的录音小样中
It works to a degree and allowing us to hear
这样做 在某种程度上 让我们一瞥
how Genesis could have sounded had he been chosen to be the vocalist.
如果他被选为Genesis主唱的话 会是什么样
Certainly the results seem to me to be similar to that of Anthony Philips singing.
注：Anthony Philips是Genesis原先的吉他手 由于怯场而离队
看上去更像是Anthony Philips唱歌的感觉
See what you think.
你们听听看
For the last of these recreations, we hear the ex-Hollies singer Alan Clarke singing.
还有最后一个要还原的 这位是前Hollies乐队的主唱Alan Clarke
Here this 1973 track, "People of a Kind", is mixed in with Squonk.
他在1973演唱的People of a Kind将会叠录在Squonk器乐之上
It's believed that Clarke was also a contender for the vacant singer position.
当时普遍认为Clarke也是主唱的人选
His name features on a list in a published Genesis biography.
他的名字出现在Genesis传记里的一张名单上
Certainly, his vocal delivery holds up very well against the familiar Genesis track.
显然 他的声色能和大家熟知的Genesis歌曲配合得很好
One can only imagine that his well-established position in the music industry
可想而知 因为他在音乐界的地位很高
may have deterred the band from ultimately considering him.
所以乐队最终没有选择他当主唱
The completed album was the first to feature individual songwriting credits.
注：在此之前，署名只有"Genesis"，而Pound专辑的署名是"全员创作所有歌曲"
在这张专辑中 他们第一次写上了每一首歌的署名
Thus, for the first time, allowing listeners to know who wrote what formally.
听众们可以头一回正式知道每首歌的具体作者了
It leaves little doubts as to who the main songwriter in the band really was
不过这也留下了一点困惑 谁到底是乐队的主要创作者
as it is Tony Banks who receives a songwriting credit on each of the album's tracks.
毕竟Tony Banks在专辑里的每首歌都有署名
Let's now explore each of these tracks in depth,
让我们深入探索 找出更多吧
and find out a little bit more about them...
Although the bulk of this song was written by Banks, Collins and Rutherford alone,
尽管这首歌的大部分都是由Banks Collins和Rutherford编写的
it's actually Steve Hackett who arguably provides the strongest moments on it.
但显然 Steve Hackett编写了这首歌中最带劲的部分
That said Collins' drumming is also sensational here.
当然 Collins的鼓声也很令人印象深刻
It's a real measure of the song's status.
这很好体现出了这首歌给人的感觉
From its daunting opening to its thrilling freeform climax,
这首歌开场激扬人心 变化自由多样 力度十足
it leaves listeners in no doubt that the band are back and with a vengeance!
很明显乐队带着一腔复仇的欲望 回归到大众的视野
It's a similar album opener to Selling England's "Dancing with the moonlight Knight".
专辑开头和Pound专辑的开幕曲很相似
And has to be one of the greatest songs that the band ever recorded,
可以说是这个乐队最伟大 最重要的一首歌
and certainly the most important song that they ever made.
Because I think if this track had failed, and failed to grip you into this new album,
要是这首歌失败了 没有吸引你继续听这个新专辑
I doubt you'd be watching this video now:-P
估计你也不会点进这个视频
This gentle ballad provides the perfect calm after the previous storm.
在上一首风云变幻之后 这首平静的民谣让听众平静了下来
The song was created from two existing tracks.
这首歌由两首歌拼接而成
The main intro and verse parts are from Steve Hackett.
引子和主歌部分是Steve Hackett写的
And they're perfectly complemented by a chorus and ending from Banks,
在此基础上 Banks写的副歌和结尾完美补全了这首歌
who states that this was his favourite track on the album.
Banks说在这张专辑里 他最喜欢这首歌
It's a rare moment when the two band mates collaborated.
这俩人能合作 还挺少见了
From here onwards, the relationship would begin to sour.
毕竟到后面 他们俩关系变差了
As an aside, the track received a rare introduction by Steve Hackett
另说一句 在现场演出前 Steve Hackett会介绍一两句
before it was played at live concerts.
Originally titled "Indians", Squonk's lyrics are based on a character and a book
Sqounk原先叫做Indians 而歌词是从William Cox写的
called "Fearsome creatures in the slumber woods" by writer William Cox.
Fearsome creatures in the slumber woods上面的主角和情节取材
The Squonk itself is a creature conscious of his ugly condition
Squonk这个生物很在意自己丑陋的外表
and he hides away in the Pennsylvanian forest as a consequence.
因此 他在宾夕法尼亚的森林里隐居
It was this first song written for the album and it shows
这是乐队为这张专辑写的第一首歌 体现了他们
a band free of the burden of the Lamb, and Gabriel's often heavyweight lyrics.
从Lamb专辑的影响和Gabriel晦涩的歌词中解放出来
In fact, the song is often thought to be about Gabriel himself.
实际上 大家普遍认为这首歌内容是关于Gabriel的
The Squonk animal is also referenced in the Steely Dan song,
在这首歌录制两年前 Squonk就在Steely Dan写的一首歌中出现了
recorded two years prior to this.
And considering Rutherford's liking for Steely Dan though,
考虑到Rutherford喜欢Steedy Dan
it's probable that this is the influence of the song's title and subject matter.
也许就是那首歌影响了这首歌的题目和主题
It's a bold and stomping Rutherford track
这首歌由Rutherford编曲 节奏强烈 血气方刚
reminiscent of Led Zeppelin's Kashmir and Levee Breaks.
让人联想到Led Zeppelin的Kashmir和Levee Breaks
Next you'll hear an isolated drum track from The Levee Breaks
接下来你将听到Collins随着Levee Breaks的鼓声唱歌
SuperBart: Bonzo yyds!
with Collins singing on top.
There is something of a similarity.
显然这两者有些相似之处
This beautiful and often overlooked Tony Banks number
这首优美的歌由Tony Banks编写 经常被忽视
has a similar construction to what he would repeat on One for the Vine.
这首歌的结构和他将在One for the Vine里体现的很相似
注：Genesis - Wind & Wuthering - One for the Vine
这张专辑我强烈推荐:-D
It has an almost complete absence of Steve Hackett,
这首歌完全没有Hackett的参与
and it's dominated by Banks as overlapping piano parts.
由Banks的重叠的钢琴音符所主导
It's one of only two tracks on the album that was never performed live.
整张专辑有两首歌从来没有现场演出过 这个是其中之一
It's lyrics are astonishing in their sophistication and imagery
这首歌歌词十分精致 想象力十足 十分有水平
and it's perhaps another song about their recently departed singer
兴许又是一首关于离队主唱Gabriel的歌曲
with its ideas of constantly yearning for pastures new.
毕竟歌词大意是要寻找一片新的天地
注：pastures指一片由青草覆盖的土地
Phil Collins have played the Artful Dodger as a teenager in a production of Oliver,
Collins小时候 曾经在Oliver剧中演过Artful Dodger
注：Artful Dodger是雾都孤儿里面的扒手
and here he reprises that role in his cockney best.
他在这首歌中 又一次在伦敦东城客串了这位
It's a comedy song that follows in the footsteps of the
这首歌充满幽默气息 之前专辑里面也有类似的歌
注：Harold The Barrel from Nursery Cryme
Get 'em Out by Friday from Foxtrot
The Battle of Epping Forest from Selling England by the Pound
Harold The Barrel, Get 'em Out by Friday and Epping Forest.
Essentially it's a Banks song, but it features some fantastic playing by the whole band.
本质上 这是首Banks的歌曲
但乐队全体成员在这首歌中都有出色表现
But it's really co-writer Collins that makes this song vividly come to life.
但让这首歌栩栩如生的 还得是协作者Phil Collins
The fifth song on the album is completely different
它表现出来的风格和音调 和前面歌的完全不同
in style and tone to everything that's perceiving.
And again, it shows that the band are more than capable of
当然 这也体现了他们确实经受住了Gabriel离队的冲击
weathering the storm of Gabriel's departure.
This is a beautiful Mike Rutherford ballad that
这首由Mike Rutherford写的民谣预示了
pre-empts the more uncomplicated love songs that
他将在八十年代和九十年代写很多的口水歌
that he especially would write over the 80s and 90s.
It was written with the express intention that Collins would sing it,
这首歌写出来 就是为了让Collins唱
similar to his cameo appearance on Selling England's More Fool Me,
有点像Selling England里面的小调More Fool Me
The band played it live over many years, but it was perhaps most effectively played
乐队在现场表演过很多回 但在2007年重聚演唱会上
in a poignant version on their 2007 reunion tour.
他们经常演奏一个更凄美的版本
SuperBart：我的童年像小鸟一样不回来:-(
This is the second track on the album to be written exclusively by Tony Banks.
这是这张专辑中 第二首由Tony Banks独立写出来的歌
Here, the lyrics are based on a neanderthal tribe
歌词则是改编自William Golding写的
found in William Golding's novel The Inheritors.
小说The Inheritors里的尼安德特部落
In a 1976 interview the band claimed that they were making a cartoon
在一次1976年的访谈中 乐队说他们想为每首歌
to accompany this song, but it's failed to materialize.
画一张漫画 不过最终没有实现
Banks have stated that the inspiration for this jaunty piano track
Banks说歌曲中轻快的钢琴声 受到了Beatles的Getting Better影响
was the Beatles track Getting Better.
The song was originally written in 1972 and intended for the Foxtrot album.
这首歌原写于1972年 本来是为了Foxtrot专辑准备的
One can imagine they're having a similar role to that of Willow Farm
真要放进Foxtrot专辑的话 那就是Supper Ready里面的
注：Willow Farm部分在Supper's Ready里的10分钟到15分钟
in Supper's Ready, as their introductions are quite similar.
Willow Farm部分 毕竟引入部分十分相似
A superb finale and one of the many examples of Genesis bookending an album
十分漂亮的结尾曲 串烧了这张专辑里的其他歌曲
with musical themes from other tracks.
This Collins inspired instrumental incorporates both elements of Squonk and Volcano.
Collins从Sqounk和Volcano两首歌中提取元素 并放在一起
Furthermore, hidden at the very end of the track,
还有 在歌曲的结尾 Collins在小声地唱Supper's Ready的最后一句
Collins can be faintly heard saying the closing lines from Supper's Ready:
"There's an angel standing in the sun, free to get back home".
"天使沐浴在阳光下 自由地回家去了"
Collins has stated that the rhythmic nature of the track
Collins说 这首歌的节奏本源是Santana的Promise of a Fisherman
was inspired by the Santana track "Promise of a Fisherman".
The one notable outtake from the album is the track It's Yourself.
还有一首值得注意的It's Yourself 录好了但没有收进专辑
It was originally demoed during at Headley Grange during the Lamb writing sessions.
原先是在Headley Grange写Lamb专辑期间 录制的小样
And its lyrics and title seem to reference the narcissistic quality of Rael,
歌词和题目看上去和Rael的自恋有关
注：Rael是Lamb专辑里，故事的主人公
and one can easily imagine this track being used in the latter part of the Lamb album.
很容易联想到 这首歌可以用在Lamb专辑的后面
Perhaps replacing something like In The Rapids.
可能替代In The Rapids那首歌
The track was ultimately issued as a b-side to the "Ripples" single,
这首歌最终给Ripples歌曲单曲做B面了
and it includes a section that would be reused in Los Endos
歌曲里面有一段 最终用在了Los Endos里面
before it ventures off into a pastoral soundscape.
就在后面进入田园意像之前的过渡部分之前
It's original title was "Beloved Summer"
本来是叫"Beloved Summer"
and it really suits that kind of ethereal quality of the of the latter sections.
确实挺适合那张专辑后面的气氛
It's been thought that the track would have been used also to
有人认为这首歌的某些部分在其他歌曲中
link other songs together, most notably, Mad Man Moon.
也出现了 最明显的是Mad Man Moon
There's a similarity between the ending of it and the opening of Mad Man Moon.
这首歌的结尾部分和Mad Man Moon开头有相似之处
It segues very well into it. Let's have a listen see what you think.
这两首歌过渡得非常自然 来感受一下吧
A Trick of the Tail was released on the 2nd of February 1976,
A Trick of the Tail发行于1976年2月2日
reaching number 3 in the UK charts and 31 in the US charts.
冲到了英国排行榜第三 美国排行榜第三十一名
These were both higher placings than the Lamb.
排名都比Lamb专辑高
By June of that year, the album had sold a hundred thousand copies,
到了那年六月 专辑已经售出了超过十万份
helping the band clear a substantial debt that they'd accrued during the Lamb tour.
帮助乐队还清了在Lamb专辑巡演期间欠下的大量债务
The cover was created by artist Colin Elgie
封面由Colin Elgie在Hipgnosis设计组指导下绘制
under the direction of the Hipgnosis design team.
It was an unusual step for Hipgnosis who usually created stark photographic pieces.
对于经常创作拍摄作品的Hipgnosis来说 这回很不寻常
注：各位可以去看看Wish You Were Here的封面，那些都是拍的
This cover features an array of Victorian style line drawings,
封面则是一系列维多利亚时代风格的白描画
each depicting different characters from the songs.
每一个人物都对应着专辑里的歌曲
It's wonderfully framed in a sepia tone cover
这些画衬托在棕褐色的纸上
that really complements the storybook nature of the album.
完美体现了这张专辑的故事性
You can see here some mock covers based on other Colin Elgie drawings.
你可以看看这些根据Colin Elgie画风绘制的封面
The album was greeted by unanimous praise and the UK's leading music press.
这张专辑获得了英国主要音乐媒体的一致好评
Chris Welsh of Melody Maker gave a glowing report
Melody Maker杂志的Chris Welsh对这张专辑赞不绝口
commenting that the overall production sound was better than ever.
评论说这张专辑的总体声效制作 比之前的要好
The NME echoed this and also commented about
NME杂志也这么说 还评论说这张专辑完美的制作水平
the album's immaculate production values.
And they observantly made reference to the fact that
他们还敏锐地提到了一个事实
the band was starting to distance themselves from things likes Yes and ELP.
乐队正在将风格从诸如Yes和ELP那样的转变开来
Sounds paper gave it five stars and commented that
Sounds Paper给了个五星好评 评论说
although the band was starting to sound more commercial,
尽管整个乐队开始偏商业化了
they hadn't sacrificed anything in terms of their musicianship or artistic credibility.
在音乐和创造力方面 他没有任何妥协
All three of these major music paper reviews reflect on a band
这三个主要报纸的评论体现了乐队充满着信心和勇气
that was full of reassured confidence that
not only had they coped with Gabriel's departure, but they were better for it.
他们不仅克服了Gabriel离队的影响 而且更加成功了
That seems to be the impression that comes across in the reviews at the time.
在当时评论看来 这确实挺让人印象深刻
The band's next job was to take the album out on the road.
乐队的下一个人任务 就是带着专辑去巡演
For this, the drummer Bill Bruford, who Phil had watched regularly
为了巡演 Yes早期的鼓手Bill Bruford
in Yes's early days, was recruited as an on-stage drummer,
被雇进来当现场鼓手 Phil早年经常去看他演出
allowing Phil Collins to step up forward and sing.
这样Phil就可以站在观众面前唱歌了
Bill Bruford: Drums
Bruford's exemplary playing was a perfect foil for Collins
Bruford教科书般的演奏 足以和Collins相衬托
SuperBart：毕竟是Robert Fripp看上的人
and the two combined brilliantly when playing together
他们俩台上演奏两个鼓 配合得十分漂亮
in shows with two drum kits on stage,
something that became a Genesis standard from here on in.
这个以后也成了Genesis演唱会的某种标配了
The band had three rehearsal days in Pinewood Studios in England,
在去加拿大和美国巡演之前
before they jetted out for a Canadian and American tour.
他们在英国的Pinewood Studios排练了三天
It was the Canadian audience that first saw the band
在1976年3月27日 加拿大的乐迷们第一次看到
in their new incarnation on the 27th of March, 1976.
这支脱胎换骨的乐队
Phil Collins has admitted that on that gig his hands were trembling,
Phil Collins承认过 在那个现场上 他的手在哆嗦
and he had a piece of paper on it with handwritten notes
为了记一些给观众的话 他自己写了个便条 时光如梭啊
as to what to say for the audience... How times changed!
The setlist combined old and new tracks, and for the first time,
节目单上有老歌 也有新歌 而且头一回
introduced medleys into the band setlist, something that
将组曲写进了节目单 他们之后也会经常这么做
that they would again increasingly include.
Perhaps the most intriguing addition to the setlist
也许节目单上最耐人寻味的一首歌 就是这首White Mountain了
was the inclusion of the track White Mountain,
which was from the Trespass album, something that Collins never even recorded.
这是Trespass上的歌 Collins没有参与录制
Overall it's an almost perfect album. Granted.
总体来说 这个专辑接近完美
It doesn't have the mystique and the atmosphere of maybe Selling England or Foxtrot,
它没有Selling England或Foxtrot那样的神秘气氛
注：这两张专辑的歌词，要没人解释，我看不明白:-(
or the cinematic order and wonder of The Lamb,
或者The Lamb那样的戏剧性和想象力
注：我听了三遍，都不知道这张专辑讲了什么故事:-P
and perhaps, it's not as brave and adventurous as Nursery Cryme or Trespass,
或者说 没有Nursery Cryme和Trespass那样的勇敢冒险属性
注：这两张专辑里的歌，都是一个一个小故事，不过Musical Box很怪诞
Trespass听上去很舒服呢:-)
but somehow this album seems to beat them all.
但不知为何 这张专辑能把它们都给比下去
I wouldn't say it's my personal favourite,
我不会说这是我个人的最爱
but being objective, I've got to say this is their best.
但客观地说 这张专辑是他们的最佳
Tony Banks: Keyboard
本视频由SuperBart翻译 原作者rael nyc发布于2021年11月15日
字幕下载：https://github.com/BenderBolg/Subtitles
I hope you've enjoyed learning a bit more about it. I really enjoyed researching this.
希望大家喜欢看 从中知道更多知识 查资料的时候我很享受
Steve Hackett: Guitar
As a lifelong Genesis fan, it's been intriguing to
作为终生的Genesis粉丝 这么多年来
Mick Rutherford: Bass
still discover new things about this band, so many years on.
还能探索到到乐队的新东西 好奇妙呢
Phil Collins: Drums and Vocal
So there you have it - Genesis, A Trick of the Tail.
好啦 Genesis的A Trick of the Tail就给大家介绍到这里了